# JOSEPHINE WAIRIMU

# Full Stack Software Development Apprentice

Innovative fresh graduate with enthusiasm in learning, an excellent verbal and written communication skills with In-depth vast knowledge in HTML, cascading style sheet, JavaScript, Miro, figma UI/UX, network setup, configuration, testing, troubleshooting, and a Customer service expert. Attentive to detail, trustworthy, well organized, who is under learning new roles of acquiring knowledge and embraces new technologies, developing professional and achieving excellence in all that I do. I'm driven by achievement and take new challenges.

## **Professional Experience**

Full Stack Software Development Apprentice.

Apprentice Cloud Limited, Nairobi, Westlands.

\*Gained experience in Miro, Figma ,Jira,Html

,Cascading style sheet ,Javascript, React Js,

Tailwind CSS, and JSON Server.

confidently can service a client from idea to a full

developed website.

\*Gained experience in UI/UX design and Bootstrap coding.

# **Projects**

Git:https://github.com/Wairimujosephine001

2022-04 - 2022-05: To-do App

React and Tailwind CSS

Figma design: https://www.figma.com

/file/jK00JPGqrXPOAPzBQhKjPu/TODO-LIST?node-

id=0%3A1

GitHub pages: https://wairimujosephine001.github.io

/AppTodo/

GitHub repository: https://github.com/Wairimujosephine001/AppTodo.git

#### Contact

#### **Address**

Kiambu, Kenya 10772

#### Phone

+254 704286676

#### E-mail

wairimujosephine01@gmail.

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com /in/josephinewairimu

#### **WWW**

https://wjosephine.apprenticecloud.com/

## Languages

English

Swahili

#### Skills

Technical troubleshooting

Networking issues

Hardware and software installation

UI/UX design

HTML, CSS, Javascript

React and Tailwind CSS

Bootstrap

Git

Figma and Miro

2022-02 – 2022-03: Akan Name Generator

JavaScript and Bootstrap

Figma design: https://www.figma.com

/file/OB8v2KvOdHGuXf5r8CcvT9/Akan?node-

id=0%3A1

GitHub pages: https://github.com/timmoh-

king/akanproject.git

GitHub repository: https://github.com/timmoh-

king/akanproject.git

2022-02 - 2022-03

JavaScript and Bootstrap

Figma design: https://www.figma.com

/file/4yAxSQHmGfK47LNeZAda3f/masterpiece-

project%2Fcinema-booking

GitHub pages: <a href="https://wairimujosephine001.github.io">https://wairimujosephine001.github.io</a>

/cimema-booking/

GitHub repository: https://github.com

/Wairimujosephine001/cimema-booking.git

### Strengths

Hardworking
Positive Attitude
Willingness and quick to
learn
Innovative thinking
Attentive to detail
Leadership Skill
Self-directed

Good communication skills

# **Work History**

# 2022-01 - Sales Executive Manager Current

Lavatec HomeFibre, Kiambu

- Increased revenue by implementing effective sales strategies in sales cycle process from prospecting leads through close.
- Analyzed past sales data and team performance to develop realistic sales goals.
- Enhanced success of advertising strategies by boosting engagement through social media and other digital marketing approaches.
- Grew sales and boosted profits, applying proactive management strategies and enhancing sales training.
- Developed sales strategy based on research of consumer buying trends and market conditions.
- Held meetings with director to identify techniques to overcome sales obstacles.

- Exceeded sales goals by implementing aggressive sales programs, overhauling processes and facilitating market development.
- Researched sales opportunities and possible leads to exceed sales goals and increase profits.

## 2021-04 - IT Intern

2021-07

2019-05

Nairobi Women's Hurlingham, Nairobi

- Assisted IT team members by crafting project research material for implementation.
- Researched new technologies to boost information security.
- Aided problem resolution measures and suggested patches and hardware, software and network troubleshooting alternatives.
- Supported IT department in handling technology rollout and maintenance.
- Tested systems to identify root causes to problems and uncover bugs.
- Worked with high-performing teams in Agile environment.
- Monitored and logged daily server tasks and reports.
- Replaced defective components and upgraded office equipment per technology plan.
- Supported computer laboratory users with hardware, software, and connectivity issues across both Windows and Mac platforms.
- Resolved Internet and wireless and wired network access problems.
- Installed application software and upgrades, virus protection, and drivers.
- Backed up administrative departments in back file scanning and document management imports.
- Updated firmware, pushed out files via FTP and troubleshot connectivity issues with remote monitoring equipment.

# 2019-01 - Supervisor and ICT Head Department

Modern Hotel Mwea, Mwea

- Applied strong leadership talents and problemsolving skills to maintain team efficiency and organize workflows.
- Networking and solving software challenges in

the Hotel.

- Created successful work schedules for each team member to maintain deadlines and fully staff shifts.
- Achieved results by working with staff to meet established targets.
- Mentored newly hired employees on operating equipment and safety and developed training manual to use for reference.
- Interviewed, hired and trained new employees for production positions.
- Set overall vision and provided team leadership.

# 2018-01 - Computer Teacher 2018-08

Jerusalem Star Academy, Ruiru

- Tested and evaluated student progress to determine effectiveness and impact of teaching methods, materials and projects.
- Invigilated and graded projects, quizzes and examinations.
- Managed and maintained computer systems, equipment and mobile devices by troubleshooting hardware and software issues, cleaning out keyboards and wiping down computer surfaces.
- Resolved problems, improved operations and provided exceptional service.
- Conducted research, gathered information from multiple sources and presented results.

### Education

# 2017-05 - Bachelor's of Business Information 2022-12 Technology: Degree in Information Technology

Kabarak University - Nakuru

# 2013-01 - Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

Mugutha Secondary School - Kiambu

- Awarded Certificates in Mathematics contest.
- Elected Captain of Education and Library.
- Member of a Basket Ball Club.

## 2004-01 - Kenya Certificate of Primary Education

|  | Member of Christian Union.   |
|--|--|
|  | Member of Football Club.   |
| 2022-03 -                                | Full Stack Software Development:   |
| Current                                  | Apprenticeship   |
|  | <ul> <li>Apprentice Cloud - Nairobi</li> <li>Awarded Certificate in Digital Apprenticeship Masterclass.</li> <li>Continuing education in Advance Masterclass Apprenticeship.</li> <li>Gained In-depth knowledge in HTML, React, cascading style sheet, java script and knowledge in Low and High Fidelity design.</li> <li>Carried out day-to-day duties accurately and efficiently.</li> <li>Participated in continuous improvement by generating suggestions, engaging in problem-solving activities to support teamwork.</li> <li>Proved successful working within tight deadlines</li> </ul> |
| Certificati                              | and fast-paced atmosphere.   |
| Certificati                              |  |
|  | ons  |
| 2016-03                                  | Anunual Mathematics Contest.   |
| 2016-03<br>2016-05                       | Anunual Mathematics Contest.  National Mathematics Contest   |
| 2016-03<br>2016-05<br>2017-05            | Anunual Mathematics Contest.  National Mathematics Contest  Computer Packages  |
| 2016-03<br>2016-05<br>2017-05<br>2022-03 | Anunual Mathematics Contest.  National Mathematics Contest  Computer Packages  |
| 2016-03<br>2016-05<br>2017-05<br>2022-03 | Anunual Mathematics Contest.  National Mathematics Contest  Computer Packages  Digital Apprenticeship  Passion for technology, customers and commercial  |
| 2016-03<br>2016-05<br>2017-05<br>2022-03 | Anunual Mathematics Contest.  National Mathematics Contest  Computer Packages  Digital Apprenticeship  Passion for technology, customers and commercial savviness.  Solving challenges and learning more in the new  |

Outside career I am as well interested in making friends and networking as we try to share ideas on

the business environment.

Jerusalem Star Academy - Ruiru

2012-11

#### **Hobbies**

I enjoy reading non-fiction books, building computer networks, solving purzels and socializing.

#### **Referees**

Name: Kevin Gitau Kamau

Profession: Ass.Human Resource Manager

Company: Nairobi Women's Hospital

Phone Number: +254723876125 Email: kamaukevin777@gmail.com

Name: James Mwangi Gichimu

Profession: Founder and CEO Appreciate cloud

Company: Apprentice Cloud Phone Number:+254727309037

Email: apprentice.cloud@gmail.com.

Name: Amos Mwangangi

Profession: ICT HOD Nairobi Women's Hurlingham

Company: Nairobi Women's Hospital

Phone Number:+254703519945 Email: amwangangi@google.com